Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/psamria (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Data Analysis
Problem Solving
Machine Learning

Certifications

Master of Science
Mastering Data Analysis in Excel
Managing Big Data with MySQL
Data Visualization and
Communication with Tableau
Business Metrics for Data-Driven
Companies

Honors-Awards

Soccer

Outstanding Contribution to Sports

Prerit Samria

Data Analyst | Machine Learning United States

Summary

I believe that passion, punctuality, and diligence are the traits that reflect me the most as an individual. My background in sports makes me a team player. I believe that for a project to be successful, the whole team needs to have the same goal and work towards achieving it every day.

With the resources being limited for every organization, it is important to ensure that every process is done optimally and thus I chose Operations Research as my major. Operations Research is a field of mathematics that helps us to arrive at optimal or near-optimal solutions to complex decision-making problems by employing techniques such as mathematical modeling, statistical analysis, and mathematical optimization.

Experience

L&T Technology Services Limited QA Engineer July 2021 - Present (1 year 10 months)

Client Location: John Deere Intelligent Solutions Group

Northeastern University
Graduate Teaching Assistant and Grader
January 2020 - April 2021 (1 year 4 months)
Greater Boston Area

State Street Global Advisors
Quantitative Research Analyst Co-op
July 2020 - December 2020 (6 months)
Boston, Massachusetts, United States

WIRTGEN GROUP Supply Chain Analyst May 2017 - July 2017 (3 months) Windhagen, Germany

New Holland Fiat India Pvt. Ltd. Supply Chain Analyst May 2016 - July 2016 (3 months)

Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India

Education

Northeastern University

Master of Science - MS, Operations Research \cdot (2019 - 2021)

Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi
Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Production and Industrial
Engineering · (2014 - 2018)

Sanskriti School

All India Senior School Certificate Examination, Class 12, Science & Mathematics \cdot (2014)